# Iris (Xiaobi) Pan

# Product Designer

**Address** New York, NY - Open To Remote Work

www http://irispan.net

**Phone** (617) 899-7188

E-mail irisxpan@gmail.com

Iris Pan is a **strategic** and **interdisciplinary designer** with **8+ years'** experience **leading omni-channel product design and innovation** from start to finish. Coming from an **Engineering + Design + Tech** background, Iris is able to dissolve boundaries between different fields, merge the **digital and the physical**, and use constraints as fuels for **creative problem solving**.

Over the years, Iris has been passionately exploring how **new interface technology** married with **human-centered design and storytelling** can engage people at a deeper level.



## **Education**

Aug 2017 - Harvard University

May 2019 Master in Design Studies (Tech Focus) - Cambridge, MA

Feb 2018 - MIT Media Lab

May 2019 Cross-Registration On ARVR, Design Innovation - Cambridge, MA

Sep 2008 - Zhejiang University

Jun 2013 Bachelor of Engineering (Industrial Design Major) - Hangzhou, China



# **Work History**



## Mastercard Labs - Sr. UX Design Engineer

New York, USA

- Lead New Interface + New Commerce Experience Prototyping: created 3+ ARVR/ IOT-based demos to showcase Mastercard's solutions and engage customers through hybrid-media storytelling —e.g., the virtual unattended store interactive tour, VR Priceless Land demo, etc. 3 patents filed and to be exhibited at multiple summits.
- Co-lead Large-Scale Cross-Functional New Product Development: 4 projects ramped up/2 products launched to date —e.g., the Blockchain-Based Smart Commerce Platform, B2B
   Payment VisionType, Marketplace Empower Solution, etc. Led design workshops and weekly reviews with SVPs, iterated and produced design deliverables on time.
- Rapid UX Prototyping for Early-Stage Projects: supported ideation and prototyping for internal
  incubator projects which later became the Priceless Planet Coalition (now live), for instance.

#### 2017 - 2017 CI&T - Sr. UX Designer

Shanghai, China

- Designed the ChickVacc app for Merial Animal Health Ltd. Enhanced poultry farmers' work efficiency with a 30% increase in chicken vaccination rate.
- Evangelized the Lean + Agile UX approach on behalf of CI&T China (e.g., gave UX strategy talks at **HK CityU**, etc.) and influenced clients' UX strategy.
- Redesigned the official website for CI&T, a global digital solution company. Helped elevate brand image and win major clients including Coca-Cola China.

### 2015 - 2016 COC (A Creative Agency) - Interaction Designer

Shanghai, China

- Invented a first-of-its-kind hybrid retail experience, Love Cassette, that combines in-store human-machine interaction with online personalized-content sharing to achieve a seamless interaction + business loop. Toured nationally with multi-million visits and profits.
- Created a double-player Kinect game for Bosch's product launch campaign with 100k+ offline participants and online sharing in a month. Increased sales by 30%.
- Originated a gesture-based interactive experience for client. Featured by Asia Design & Management Forum (20k visits/3 days). Client's search rate raised by 50% and sales doubled.

### 2012 - 2015 Freelance - Designer

Shanghai, China

 Delivered omnichannel brand and UX design solutions for 10+ mid-sized Chinese companies to help differentiate their brand and expand customer base. Established design consistency across various platforms (e.g. web, app, video, prints, physical store...).

# **Skills**

- UX Design & Prototyping, Design Thinking, Iterative Design, Storyboarding
- Game Design, ARVR Design & Development (Unity + Unreal), Computational Design, C# programming
- Industrial Design, 3D Modeling, Digital Fabrication, Electrical Design & Engineering, Robotics
- Sound Design, Animation, Video Production, Branding, Motion Graphics, Web Design



- 14th International Conference on Design Principles & Practices Speaker 2020
- Apple Hardware Technology Group Guest speaker 2019
- IEEE GEM (Games, Entertainment and Media) Conference Speaker & Panelist 2019
- New England Graduate Media Symposium Speaker & Panelist 2019
- A' Design Award Generative, Algorithmic and Parametric category Winner 2019
- Red Dot Concept Design Award Winner 2011













